# Hello. I'm Lee Eason.

A "front lines" leader and high-energy, business-focused agent of organizational change with over 20 years of experience in SaaS and agile teams. I am a high EQ, self-aware leader and conference speaker on DevOps, agile, and management.

## **Skills**

- Technology Leadership
- Organizational Change
- Agile
- DevOps
- Test Automation
- Scalability
- Software Engineering
- SaaS
- User Experience

## **Tools**

- AWS
- Open Source
- Databases
- Python
- JavaScript
- CI/CD
- Git
- Node.js

## **Education**

2001 | B.S

### HISTORY EDUCATION

Minor: Computer Science Pensacola Christian College

## **Accolades**

2018 - 2019

### DEVELOPER + HEAD

Ipreo Leadership Program: early careers program for entire firm that hired 65 people the first year and 600 in 2019 resulting in \$6mm savings in recruitment costs

## **Experience**

#### 2017 - PRESENT

#### FOUNDER, CEO

#### TEKATA.io

Tekata.io provides online skill gap analysis that helps organizations optimize hiring and training, as well as targeted consulting for DevOps and Cloud digital transformation.

- Consulted with Edward Jones in Q1 2020 to help improve DevSecOps maturity and create a cloud adoption strategy.
- Our SaaS tool utilizes serverless architecture: backend API in Python on AWS Lambda and RDS Aurora, frontend hosted in S3 and served by Cloudfront, BA runs on Quicksight. It features zero-downtime automated deployment pipelines for all components.

#### SEPT 2019 - FEB 2020

#### CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

#### **SOFTPRO**

SoftPro is the number one provider of mortgage title and escrow software in the US. They are a wholly owned subsidiary of Fidelity National Financial (FNF).

- Responsible for all product development, operations, and IT related functions of the company and managed an organization of over 150 people.
- Increased predictability of all ten software development teams from an average of 62% to 95%.
- Led the organization through the creation of a career and performance management framework, the first in SoftPro's history.
- Created formal training programs to help engineering staff learn modern skills related to public cloud and Azure development.

#### JULY 2015 - SEPT 2019

#### EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

#### **IHS MARKIT**

Joined IHS through their acquisition of Ipreo and led the DevOps integration effort. Also managed the SRE guild, which included a small central team and 60+ product embedded engineers supporting 160+ AWS accounts and \$20mm+ annual spend.

- Created a global dev tools group that serviced 3000 software developers with 14 tools.
- Led adoption of a service ownership model, focusing on observability and automation of failure recovery and incident response.
- Partnered with IT to build shared tools used by all cloud teams to improve financial and security compliance, leading to 20% improvement in CIS scores and \$200k in cost savings.

#### DIRECTOR OF DEVOPS

#### IPREC

Responsible for driving organizational and cultural change from traditional, separate operations and development teams, to integrated, cross functional DevOps. Led a DevOps transformation across 70+ development teams, supporting 30+ products.

- Deployment related manual work reduced over 95%; Friction/delays reduced from 350+ days per month to 2 days per month; 24% decrease in defects; deploy frequency increased from 100 to 9,000+ per month across all environments and products with no increase in support staff.
- Shifted the firm from a NOC support model to a team-first, service ownership model for datacenter hosted services, driving teams to improve product stability and adopt monitoring best practices.
- Drove firm wide adoption of modern development tools including GitHub Enterprise, Splunk, TFS, SonarQube, Artifactory, Slack, Jira, Confluence, and TeamCity.

#### **JAN 2013 - JUL 2015**

#### CHIEF ARCHITECT

#### **ULTRALINQ**

UltraLinq is a cloud based PACS, offering a web-based solution for the medical imaging industry. We process medical studies from a variety of modalities from echo cardiology to emergency medicine. Our application must be HIPPA, HITECH, and FDA 510k compliant. We are on the leading edge of cloud-based ultrasound study viewing and archiving.

- Responsible for all software system architecture and design
- Implemented quality standards and test automation
- Led implementation of an FDA approved agile development process
- Led migration of legacy systems to fully automated AWS implementation

#### **JAN 2013 - JUL 2015**

#### PRINCIPLE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### WEBASSIGN

Used by thousands of universities and high schools, WebAssign is a leader in online homework and testing.

- Led a team that architected their next generation platform
- Microservice architecture featuring dynamic provisioning and MongoDB clusters
- Broad leadership in agile development best practices

#### **JAN 2010 - JAN 2012**

#### **TECHNICAL TEAM LEAD**

#### **iCONTACT**

Sending millions of emails per day, iContact is a large-scale online marketing platform.

- Led front end development and architecture for the top team in the company
- Led the development of new template and message editing interfaces that resulted in an 86% increase in trial conversions
- Received an Outstanding Achievement award by the CEO

## **Speaking and Writing**

## CIO Review Magazine

 $\frac{\text{https://devops.cioreview.com/cxoinsight/you-cannot-improve-what-you-do-not-measure-nid-18251-cid-99.html}{\text{https://devops.cioreview.com/cxoinsight/devops-for-the-agile-leader-nid-28902-cid-99.html}}$ 

### DevOps Transformation Case Study

Coveros Webinar, 2019

https://training.coveros.com/lvws-practical-advice-agile-leaders-during-devops-transformations

### Enterprise DevOps

DevOps Institute, Continuous ChitChat Podcast, 2019

 $\underline{https://soundcloud.com/user-146353502/continuous-chitchat-ep-22-lee-eason-jayne-groll-explore-enterprises-and-the-devops-approach}$ 

#### Interview

Delivery of Things, 2018

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5oxD4gH4PQU

### Tales from a DevOps Transformation

All Things Open, 2018

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MtPcqz1DRJo

#### Tales from a DevOps Journey

The Cloudcast Podcast, 2018

https://www.thecloudcast.net/2018/11/tales-from-devops-journey.html

#### **DevOps for Product Owners**

Deliver It Podcast, 2017

http://deliveritcast.com/ep49-devops-for-product-owners

## Enterprise DevOps: Bridging the InfoSec Gap

All Things Open, 2017

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hfY2jo\_O7wY